Guide to the Dial/Scofield Thayer Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Dial Manuscripts, 1918-28; Series III; 3.75; (9 boxes)
  - Eliot, T. S.
    - "The Possibility of a Poetic Drama", n.d. (Box 20, Folder 404)
    - "The Second Order Mind" (Box 20, Folder 405)
    - Book Reviews
      - "The Golden Ass of Apuleius", n.d. (Box 20, Folder 406)
      - "Literature, Science, and Dogma" (Box 20, Folder 407)
      - "Marianne Moore", n.d. (Box 20, Folder 408)
      - "The Oxford Jonson", n.d.
      - "The Poems, English, Latin and Greek of Richard Crashaw", 1927 (Box 20, Folder 409)
      - "Poet and Saint", 1927
      - "The Silurist", n.d. (Box 20, Folder 410)
      - " Ulysses, Order, and Myth"
    - Poetry
      - "The Hollow Men", n.d. (Box 20, Folder 411)
      - "The Waste Land," typescript, corrected by J. Sibley Watson, Jr. (Box 20, Folder 412)
  - Ellis, Havelock: "William Shenstone", 1927 May (Box 20, Folder 413)
  - Faure, Elie
    - "Les dieux", 1924 (Box 20, Folder 414)
    - "L'art vivant" [ Living Art ], n.d. (Box 20, Folder 415)
    - "Un livre sur l'art moderne", n.d. (Box 20, Folder 416)
    - "Reflexions sur la genie grec", n.d. (Box 20, Folder 417)
    - "Souvenirs d'un autodidacte", n.d. (Box 20, Folder 418)
  - Ford, Ford Madox
    - "Thus to Re-Visit" III, autograph ms. and typescript, 1920 (Box 20, Folder 419)
    - "Thus to Re-Visit" V, autograph ms., 1920 (Box 20, Folder 420)
  - Forster, E. M.: "Eliza in Chains", [1924?] (Box 20, Folder 421)
  - Fry, Roger
    - "The Anatomy of Melancholy ", n.d. (Box 20, Folder 422)
    - "The Hudson Memorial", n.d. (Box 20, Folder 423)
    - "London Statutes," autograph ms. and typescript carbon (Box 20, Folder 424)
    - "M. Marchand at the Independent Gallery" (Box 20, Folder 425)
    - "Mr. Epstein's Sculpture", n.d. (Box 20, Folder 426)
    - "Plastic Colour", n.d. (Box 20, Folder 427)
    - "The Religion of Culture", n.d. (Box 20, Folder 428)
    - "Salamanca", n.d. (Box 20, Folder 429)
  - Garnett, David: " Jacob's Room ", n.d. (Box 20, Folder 430)
  - Gor'kiï, Maksim
    - "Reminiscences of Leonid Andreyev I" (Box 20, Folder 431)
    - "Reminiscences of Leonid Andreyev II" (Box 20, Folder 432)
  - Gould, Wallace: "Two Greek Heads," Two Poems: "The Game," "Matin", n.d. (Box 20, Folder 433)
  - de Gourmont, Remy: "Dust for Sparrows," trans. by Ezra Pound
    - Manuscript in Pound's hand (Box 21, Folder 434)
    - Typescript, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 435)
  - Gregory, Alyse: "The Journal of Katherine Mansfield ", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 436)
  - Unpublished reviews, 1928-29, n.d.
  - H.D.: Three Poems: (Box 21, Folder 437)
    - "Helios" "Phaedra Remembers Crete" "Phaedra Rebukes Hippolyta", n.d.
  - Hardy, Thomas: "The Two Houses", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 438)
  - Hofmannsthal, Hugo von
    - "Honoré de Balzac", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 439)
    - "Vienna Letter", 1922 Aug (Box 21, Folder 440-41)
      See also: Oversize, Box 74, folder 1943
  - Hudson, W. H.: "Letters to Edward Garnett", 1923 (Box 21, Folder 442)
  - Joyce, James: "A Memory of the Players in a Mirror at Midnight": autograph ms., [1918] (Box 21, Folder 443)
  - Lawrence, D. H.
    - "Indians and an Englishman" (Box 21, Folder 444)
    - "Sea and Sardinia"
    - Extract I: "As far as Palermo", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 445)
    - Extract II: "Cagliari", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 446)
    - Book Review
      - "Model Americans", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 447)
    - Fiction
      - "Adolf", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 448)
      - "Glad Ghosts", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 449-51)
      - "The Man Who Loved Islands" (Box 21, Folder 452-53)
      - "Modern Love", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 454)
      - "Rex": autograph ms. signed, with ALS to Richard Aldington, [n.y. May 30] (Box 21, Folder 455)
      - "The Woman Who Rode Away," typescript; typescript with autograph corrections and additions; galleys (Box 21, Folder 456-58)
      - "Two Blue Birds", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 459)
    - Poetry
      - "The Apostolic Beasts", 1921 (Box 21, Folder 460)
      - "Pomegranate", 1920 Mar
      - "Snake", n.d.
      - Ten Poems: "November by the Sea" "Things Men Have Made" "Whatever Man Makes--" "Work" "Attila" "What Would You Fight For?" "Censors" "Sea-Weed" "Lizard" "To Let Go or Hold On?", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 461)
  - Littell, Philip: " English Prose Style ," autograph ms., n.d. (Box 21, Folder 462)
  - "Heavenly Harmony," typescript, 1928 May
  - Lowell, Amy
    - "A Bird's Eye View of E. A. Robinson", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 463)
    - "Gavotte in D-Minor" (Box 21, Folder 464)
    - "Katydids", n.d.
    - "Songs of the Pueblo Indians"
    - Three Poems: (Box 21, Folder 465)
      - "Orientation" "The Red Knight" "Decoration Day"
    - Two Poems: (Box 21, Folder 466)
      - "Sultry" "Time's Acre", n.d.
    - Lubicz-Milosz, O. W. de: "Strophes," trans. by Ezra Pound (Box 21, Folder 467)
  - Mann, Thomas
    - "German Letter," typescript, corrected by Scofield Thayer, 1922 Nov (Box 21, Folder 468)
    - "German Letter," typescripts, signed, 1925-28 (Box 21, Folder 469-71)
    - "Tolstoi," typescript, signed, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 472)
  - Mansfield, Katherine: "A Married Man's Story" (Box 21, Folder 473)
  - Mencken, H. L.: " Stephen Crane: A Study in American Letters ", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 474)
  - Modotti, Tina: "Plenipotentiary", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 475)
  - Moore, George
    - "George Moore and Granville-Barker", 1923 Aug (Box 21, Folder 476)
    - "George Moore and John Freeman", 1923 Oct (Box 22, Folder 477)
    - "Preface to The Coming of Gabrielle ", 1923 Jan (Box 22, Folder 478)
  - Moore, Marianne
    - Announcements and "Comment", 1925-29 (Box 22, Folder 479-88)
    - Articles
      - "Is the Real the Actual?", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 489)
      - "A Poet of the Quattrocento", n.d.
      - "Sir Francis Bacon", n.d.
    - Book Reviews
      - "Besitz und Gemeingut: Wolfgang Goethe, by George Brandes" (Box 22, Folder 490)
      - "The Bright Immortal Olive: Collected Poems of H.D. ", n.d.
      - " Conversations in Ebury Street, by George Moore", [n.y. Dec 17] (Box 22, Folder 491)
      - " Development, by W. Bryher", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 492)
      - "An Eagle in the Ring: Collected Poems by Vachel Lindsay"
      - "Gentle Sorcery" [Laurence Houseman], n.d. (Box 22, Folder 493)
      - " Harmonium, by Wallace Stevens", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 494)
      - "A House Party: Armed with Madness by Mary Butts", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 495)
      - "An Illustrious Doctor Admirable for Everything: Historia Calamitatum, by Peter Abelard", 1925 Nov (Box 22, Folder 496)
      - " Jacapone da Todi by Evelyn Underhill" (Box 22, Folder 497)
      - "Land and Sea and Sky and Sun"
      - " The Life of William Congreve, by Edmund Gosse", 1925 Jan (Box 22, Folder 498)
      - "'Literature, the Noblest of the Arts:' The Collected Essays and Papers of George Saintsbury ", [Jul]
      - " The Making of Americans, by Gertrude Stein", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 499)
      - " The Man Who Died Twice, by Edwin Arlington Robinson", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 500)
      - "Mr. Strachey's Past: Books and Characters by Lytton Strachey"
      - " Natives of Rock, by Glenway Wescott", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 501)
      - "'People Stare Carefully:' E. E. Cummings", n.d.
      - " Poems, by Stewart Mitchell", 1921 Jun (Box 22, Folder 502)
      - " A Portrait of George Moore, by John Freeman", n.d.
      - " The Sacred Wood, by T. S. Eliot", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 503)
      - "Thistles Dipped in Frost" [Maxwell Bodenheim], n.d. (Box 22, Folder 504)
      - "'The Trouvère's Immortal Gear:' Human Shows, by Thomas Hardy", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 505)
    - Poetry
      - "The Monkey Puzzler", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 506)
      - "Novices", n.d.
      - "An Octopus", 1924 Dec (Box 22, Folder 507)
      - "People's Surroundings" (two versions) (Box 22, Folder 508)
      - "Sea Unicorns and Land Unicorns", [1924 Nov] (Box 22, Folder 509)
      - "Silence", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 510)
      - Two Poems: "England" "Picking and Choosing", [1920 Apr] (Box 22, Folder 511)
      - Two Poems: "A Graveyard" "When I buy Pictures", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 512)
      - Two Poems: "New York" "The Labors of Hercules" (two versions), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 513-14)
  - Morand, Paul: "Turkish Night," trans. by Ezra Pound (Box 22, Folder 515)
  - Mortimer, Raymond
    - "Bombination: Chrome Yellow, by Aldous Huxley", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 516)
    - " Life and Death of Harriet Frean, by May Sinclair" (Box 22, Folder 517)
    - "London Letter" (Box 22, Folder 518)
    - "The Movement: Since Cezanne by Clive Bell", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 519)
    - "Oedipus Tyrannus: The Judge, by Rebecca West", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 520)
  - Murry, J. Middleton
    - "Moralisings on Morand: Open All Night by Paul Morand," autograph ms. (Box 22, Folder 521)
    - "The Weariness of Ivan Bunin," autograph ms., n.d. (Box 22, Folder 522)
  - Ortega y Gasset, José: [Spanish Letter], n.d. (Box 22, Folder 523)
  - Pound, Ezra
    - "Dr. Williams' Position", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 524)
    - "Guido's Relations", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 525-26)
    - " Mediaevalism and Mediaevalism: Guido Cavalcanti" (Box 22, Folder 527)
    - "Paris Letter", 1920-23 (Box 22, Folder 528-38)
    - Book Reviews
      - " Donna Mi Prega, by Guido Cavalcanti", 1928, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 539-40)
      - "Mr. Aldington's Views on Gourmont", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 541)
      - " St. George at Silone, by Alvaro Guevara", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 542)
    - Poetry
      - "Eight Poems" [Hugh Selwyn Mauberley, I-VI], n.d. (Box 22, Folder 543)
      - "Eighth Canto", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 544)
      - "Fourth Canto" See: Oversize, Box 74, folder 1944
      - "Three Cantos" (V, VI, VII), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 545)
      - "Canto XXII", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 546)
      - Part of Canto XXVII, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 547)
  - Powys, Llewellyn: Unpublished "Briefer Mentions", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 548)
  - Rilke, Rainer Maria: Nine Prose Poems, 1 leaf of printer's proof, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 549)
  - Rimbaud, Arthur: "A Season in Hell," trans. J. S. Watson, Jr., n.d. (Box 23, Folder 550)
  - Robinson, Edwin Arlington: "Inferential," typescript, signed, 1920 Jan (Box 23, Folder 551)
  - "Not Always," autograph ms., signed, n.d.
  - Russell, Bertrand
    - Articles
      - "Chinese Civilization and the West" (Box 23, Folder 552)
      - "Dreams and Facts", 1920 Feb (Box 23, Folder 553)
      - "Freedom in Education: A Protest Against Mechanism", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 554)
      - "Higher Education in China", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 555)
      - "Is Science Superstitious?", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 556)
      - "Leisure and Mechanism" (Box 23, Folder 557)
      - "Life in the Middle Ages", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 558)
      - "On Catholic and Protestant Skeptics"
      - "Psychology and Politics" (Box 23, Folder 559)
      - "Psychology and Religion" (Box 23, Folder 560)
      - "Things that Have Moulded Me", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 561)
    - Book Reviews
      - "Americanization": autograph ms., n.d. (Box 23, Folder 562)
      - "The Aroma of Evanescence," autograph ms., n.d.
      - "An Attempt to Convert Kentucky," autograph ms. and galleys (Box 23, Folder 563)
      - "Does Ethics Influence Life?", 1924 Apr (Box 23, Folder 564)
      - "The Dogmas of Naturalism", n.d.
      - "Leonardo as a Man of Science," autograph ms., n.d. (Box 23, Folder 565)
      - "Life as an Art", n.d.
      - " The Meaning of Meaning ", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 566)
      - "A Motley Pantheon", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 567)
      - "Wasted Idealism", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 568)
      - "What Is Morality?" autograph ms., n.d.
  - Saintsbury, George
    - "Colloquial", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 569)
    - "Edgar Allen Poe", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 570)
    - "Irony", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 571)
    - "Technique", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 572)
    - "Things About Blake", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 573)
    - "Xenophon", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 574)
    - Book Reviews
      - "Ambiguous Perfection: Seneca's Moral Essays ", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 575)
      - " The Letters of Abelard and Heloise, trans. by C. K. Scott-Moncrieff" (Box 23, Folder 576)
      - " Englishmen and Manners in the Eighteenth Century, by A. S. Turberville" (Box 23, Folder 577)
      - " The Golden Book ", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 578)
      - " The Hypochondriack "
      - " Medieval Rhetoric and Poetic " (Box 23, Folder 579)
      - " More Words ", n.d.
      - "Pisgah Looking both Ways", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 580)
      - " Selected Poems of Edgar Allen Poe ", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 581)
      - "Walpole Revisited", n.d.
      - " Words! Words! ", 1927 Mar (Box 24, Folder 582)
  - Sandburg, Carl
    - "Flat Waters of the West in Kansas", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 583)
    - Four Poems:
      - "Hats" "Pennsylvania" "Broken-face Gargoyles" "Jazz Fantasia", [1920 Feb, n.d.]
    - "The Lawyers Know Too Much", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 584)
    - "Slabs of the Sunburnt West", n.d.
  - Santayana, George
    - "An Aesthetic Soviet": autograph ms. and galleys (Box 24, Folder 585)
    - "A Long Way Round to Nirvana": autograph ms. (Box 24, Folder 586)
    - " Marginal Notes on Civilization in the United States ": autograph ms., n.d. (Box 24, Folder 587)
    - "On Self-Government: A Dialogue in Limbo": autograph ms. and galleys (Box 24, Folder 588-89)
    - "Overheard in Seville": autograph ms. and galleys (Box 24, Folder 590)
    - "The Sorrows of Avicenna": autograph ms., n.d. (Box 24, Folder 591)
    - "The Wisdom of Avicenna": autograph ms. and galleys (Box 24, Folder 592)
  - Schloezer, Boris de
    - "Igor Stravinsky, I," trans. by Ezra Pound (Box 24, Folder 593)
    - "Igor Stravinsky: His Technique," trans. by Ezra Pound (Box 24, Folder 594-95)
    - "Igor Stravinsky: the Problem of Style," trans. by Ezra Pound (Box 24, Folder 596)
    - "Igor Stravinsky: A Classic Art," trans. by Ezra Pound (Box 24, Folder 597-98)
  - Seldes, Gilbert: fragments, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 599)
  - Sitwell, Osbert: Malgré Lui, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 600)
  - Sitwell, Sacheverell: " Virgin Spain, by Waldo Frank", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 601)
  - Smith, Logan Pearsall
    - "English Aphorisms I", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 602)
    - "English Aphorisms II", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 603)
    - "English Aphorisms III", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 604)
    - "English Aphorisms I, II, III," galleys, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 605)
    - "First Catch Your Hare", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 606)
    - "Jeremy Taylor", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 607-08)
    - "Laconics", 1927 [Jan] (Box 24, Folder 609)
      See also: Oversize, Box 74, folder 1945
    - "Madame de Sévigné in the Country", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 610)
    - "Michael Field", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 611)
    - "On Re-Reading Pater" "Queen Victoria" (Box 24, Folder 612)
      See: Oversize, Box 74, folder 1946 "Preaching to Butterflies"
    - "Saint-Beuve", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 613)
    - ["Trivia"]: autograph ms., 1922 Mar (Box 24, Folder 614)
  - Stein, Gertrude
    - "Composition as Explanation", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 615)
    - "A Long Gay Book", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 616)
  - Stein, Leo: "Distortion," "Reality", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 617)
  - Stevens, Wallace: Five Poems: (Box 25, Folder 618)
    - "Mostly Moonlight" "Bantams in the Pine-Woods" "The Emperor of Ice Cream" "Frogs Eat Butterflies" "A High-Toned Old Christian Woman", n.d.
  - Symons, Arthur: "Thomas Hardy", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 619)
  - Thayer, Scofield
    - Announcements and "Comment", 1920-25, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 620-36)
    - Articles
      - "Berlin Letter", 1926 (Box 25, Folder 637)
      - "Compton Mackenzie," autograph ms., typescript, 1918 Nov (Box 25, Folder 638-40)
      - "Gladiators, Brown Skins, Et Cetera," autograph ms., 1921 Aug (Box 25, Folder 641)
      - "James Joyce," autograph manuscript, 1918 Sep 8 (Box 25, Folder 642)
      - "Letter to the Editors", 1925 Oct 14 (Box 25, Folder 643)
      - "Leo Stein and the Editor", 1924 Oct (Box 25, Folder 644)
      - "Two Letters," autograph mss., n.d.
      - "Two Letters," typescripts, 1924 Aug (Box 25, Folder 645)
      - "Two Letters," galleys, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 646)
    - Book Reviews
      - "Briefs on New Books," autograph ms., 1918 Jun-Sep (Box 26, Folder 647-48)
      - "Limited Horizons: Horizons, by Francis Hackett Huebsch," autograph ms., 1918 Jul (Box 26, Folder 649)
      - "Lords of Language: Oscar Wilde, by Frank Harris," autograph mss., typescript, 1918 May (Box 26, Folder 650-51)
      - Modern British Poetry, 1920 Jun (Box 26, Folder 652)
      - "Notes on New Contributors", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 653)
      - "Passionate Puppets: Nocturne, by Frank Swinnerton," autograph ms., 1918 Jun (Box 26, Folder 654)
      - "The Theatre," autograph ms., 1920-21 (Box 26, Folder 655)
      - "Three French Books," autograph ms., 1918 May (Box 26, Folder 656)
      - "A Victorian Lady: Autobiography by Margaret Asquith," autograph ms., 1921 Feb (Box 26, Folder 657)
      - "Wit and Wisdom,: South Wind by Norman Douglas," autograph ms., 1918 Aug (Box 26, Folder 658)
    - Poetry
      - "And Love Said, Let There be Rain" (Box 26, Folder 659)
      - "Le Cantique des Desirs Inassouvis", n.d.
      - "Chanson Eperdue", 1926 Oct
      - "Chanson Equivoque", n.d.
      - "Counsel to a Young Man", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 660)
      - "Crow Song", n.d.
      - "Dawn from a Railway Coach", n.d.
      - "Des Choses...", n.d.
      - "I Walk Understandingly" (Box 26, Folder 661)
      - "In Evil Time", n.d.
      - "In Which the Fingers of the Night Wind are Made to Call"
      - "Jesus Again", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 662)
      - "On A Crucifix", n.d.
      - "On the Mask of a Painter Recently Young", n.d.
      - "A Poem by Timothy Moskowitz," autograph ms., 1920 Oct (Box 26, Folder 663)
      - "A Poem", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 664)
      - "Poeme Sage", n.d.
      - "Rarement", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 665)
      - "Wherefore", n.d.
      - Unpublished poems, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 666)
  - Trueblood, Charles K. [Book Review], 1927 Aug (Box 26, Folder 667)
  - Van Vechten, Carl: "The Lady Stuffed with Pistachio Nuts: Jennifer Lorn, by Elinor Wylie", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 668)
  - Watson, James Sibley
    - "American Letter", 1921 Apr (Box 26, Folder 669)
    - Award Announcements, 1925, 1928 (Box 26, Folder 670)
    - "Comments", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 671)
    - Book Reviews
      - " The Analysis of Mind, by Bertrand Russell", 1922 Sep (Box 26, Folder 672)
      - "Blake's Paintings", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 673)
      - "Journalist Critics", n.d.
      - "A Key to the Enigmas of the World: Tertium Organum, by P. D. Ouspensky," autograph ms. and typescript (Box 26, Folder 674)
      - "The Perfumed Paraphrase of Death: Tulips and Chimneys, by E. E. Cummings" (Box 26, Folder 675)
      - "Roger Fry Is Very.. .: The Artist and Psycho-Analysis, by Roger Fry" (Box 26, Folder 676)
      - "Some Remarks on Rimbaud as Magician", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 677)
  - Wescott, Glenway
    Book Reviews
    - "Concerning Miss Moore's Observations", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 678)
    - "A Courtly Poet: A Draft of Sixteen Cantos ", n.d.
    - "A Historian of Conquests: Hernando de Soto by R. B. Cunninghame Graham" (Box 26, Folder 679)
    - "Miss Roberts' First Novel: The Time of Man ", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 680)
    - "Mr. Osbert Sitwell's Fiction", n.d.
    - "A Monument: The Spanish Farm, by R. H. Mottram", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 681)
    - Fiction
      - "Bad Han", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 682-83)
      - "Hunters", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 684)
      - "In a Thicket", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 685)
    - Poetry
      - "Natives of Rock", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 686)
      - "Three Poems: Evening Illusion", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 687)
  - Williams, William Carlos
    - "From Queens to Cats", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 688)
    - "Good.. .for what?", n.d.
    - "Impasse and Imagery" (Box 27, Folder 689)
    - "Kenneth Burke", n.d.
    - "Marianne Moore", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 690)
    - Fiction
      - "Five Prose Sketches" from A Voyage to Pagany, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 691)
      - The Venus, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 692)
    - Poetry
      - Eight Poems: "January" "Approach of Winter" "Lightning at Dawn" "The Cold Night" "Complaint" "To a Foolish Old Woman" "The Sturdy Maidservant" "Winter Trees" "Daybreak", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 693)
      - ".. .enfolding an old lady", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 694)
      - Five Poems [Four]: "the farmer in deep thought" "Our orchestra" "Of death" "The crowd at the ball game" (Box 27, Folder 695)
      - "Lines on Receiving The Dial Award," typescript, signed, [1926 Dec 3] (Box 27, Folder 696)
      - "The Men", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 697)
      - "Paterson", [1926 Dec]
      - Six Poems: "Portrait of a Lady" "To Waken an Old Lady" "The Desolate Field" "Willow Poem" "Blizzard" "Spring Storm", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 698)
      - "Struggle of Wings", [1926 Jul] (Box 27, Folder 699)
      - Three Poems: "March is a Light" "Young Sycamore" "Lines on Receiving the Dial 's Award", 1927 Jan (Box 27, Folder 700)
      - Three Poems: "On Gay Wallpaper" "The Lily" "The Source", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 701)
      - Two Poems: "The Birds" "Youth and Beauty" (Box 27, Folder 702)
      - Two Poems: "The Jungle" "The Bull", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 703)
      - "When fresh, it was sweet," typescript and revised typescript (Box 27, Folder 704-05)
  - Woolf, Virginia
    - "The Lives of the Obscure", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 706)
    - "Miss Ormerod", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 707)
    - "Mrs. Dalloway in Bond Street" (Box 27, Folder 708)
  - Yeats, William Butler
    - "A Biographical Fragment", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 709)
    - "The Bounty of Sweden", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 710-11)
    - "The Death of Synge", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 712-13)
    - [Four Years], typescript, incomplete, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 714)
    - More Memories, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 715-19)
    - "The Need for Audacity of Thought", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 720)
    - Poetry
      - "Among Schoolchildren", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 721)
      - The Cat and the Moon (Box 27, Folder 722)
      - Four Poems: "Leda and the Swan" "The Gift of Haroun-al-Rashid" "The Lover Speaks" "The Heart Replies" (Box 27, Folder 723)
      - "Meditations in Time of Civil War", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 724)
      - Michael Robertes and the Dancer, Proofs: The Cuala Press, 1920 (Box 27, Folder 725)
      - The Player Queen, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 726)
      - Ten poems: manuscript and typescript "A Meditation in Time of War" "Easter 1916" "Under Saturn" "Towards Break of Day" "Sixteen Dead Men" "The Rose Tree" "The Second Coming" "Michael Robartes and the Dancer" "On a Political Prisoner" "Demon and Beast" (Box 27, Folder 727)
      - "Thoughts Upon the Present State of the World", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 728)
- Scofield Thayer Correspondence, 1879-1931; Series IV; 8.75; (19 boxes)
  Series IV, Scofield Thayer Correspondence, is housed
  in Boxes 28-46 and contains alphabetically arranged
  correspondence. All letters have been placed in
  chronological order within each folder; individuals have
  been given separate listings whenever there are four or
  more items to or from that person. Third-party
  correspondence, unidentified, and empty envelopes are
  located at the end of the series.
  - "A" general, 1920-26 (Box 28, Folder 729)
  - Aiken, Conrad, 1920 (Box 28, Folder 730)
  - Aldington, Richard, 1920-21
  - Alger, George W., 1921 (Box 28, Folder 731)
  - Allsop, Henry, 1919, 1923
  - Anderson, Sherwood, 1920 (Box 28, Folder 732)
  - "B" general, 1907-25, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 733-34)
  - Barnes, Albert C., 1920-21 (Box 28, Folder 735)
  - Beardsley, Ellen, 1921
  - Beck, Doris, 1921-26 (Box 28, Folder 736)
  - Beerbohm, Max, 1923 (Box 28, Folder 737)
  - Bell, Clive, 1924-25
  - Belloc, Hillare, 1923
  - Bermuda Realty Co., 1924 (Box 28, Folder 738)
  - Bernays, Edward, 1920-21
  - Biermann, Georg, 1923 (Box 28, Folder 739)
  - Bigler, A. L., 1919-20 (Box 28, Folder 740)
  - Birnbaum, Martin, 1921-25 (Box 28, Folder 741)
  - Blalock, Hubert, 1920 (Box 28, Folder 742)